Norbertas Lapenas

Software Developer

An individual with a positive attitude and a natural understanding of logical thinking. Skilled at problem solving in a calm and organized manner. A team player with a self motivated mentality. Currently seeking the opportunity to start a career in "Software Development.

27 The Meadows, Oldgrange Wood, Monasterevin, Co.Kildare, Ireland.

(085) 114-9751

norbertasl.github.io
github.com/Norbertasl

PROJECTS

L2 Market DB — Python tool to parse in-qame data using OCR.

Ongoing project that take ingame images and parses the item data using "Tesseract OCR", then stores the data in a SQLite database. Future plans are to upload it into a cloud database and make a website to access it.

Source:L2 Market DB

The Monkees Website — *Website designed using "Bootstrap"*.

A retro style website designed using "Bootstrap". Simple and functional.

Source: The Monkees Preview

Website: The Monkees Preview

NumberHelp — Number converter for Android.

An Android app that converts numbers between Decimal, Hexadecimal, Octal and Binary. Has a build in check to see if the numbers entered are valid.

Source: Number Help

EDUCATION

Coursera — Machine Learning, Cryptography I and Algorithms I

2021

3 Courses I'm currently working on to gain a deeper understanding in computers and their related technology. These are self-paced courses.

Coursera — Learning How to Learn

2020

4 Week course discussing current neuroscience and psychology research relating to learning.

Code Institute — Full Stack Developer

2019

Programming Languages

Java, Python, C#, JS, SQL.

Other Developer Skills

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, API, VCS(Git), Gradle, Maven, Blender, GoDot.

Languages

English, Lithuanian, Basic Japanese (Currently Studying).

General Skills/Characteristics

Problem Solver, Motovated, Obsessed with self improvement, Logical Thinker.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

<u>3D Printers</u> - Assembled a 3D printer based of "Anter A8" design.Self taught 3D modeling

MMA/BJI - Started doing martial arts for fitness, but fell in love with it, got my BJJ blue belt and now working towards the next one...

EDUCATION Continued ...

County Kildare Leader Partnership — Business Development & Marketing 2018

Udacity — Android Development & App Design 2017

Oracle — Java SE 8 Associate Programmer Certificate

2013

DCU — B.Sc Computer Science

2010

Career Summary

A Gilligan Builders, Dublin—Construction Operative/Installer

2010-2019

Full time and part-time role since 2010. A high number of duties and responsibilities required a fast learning mentality and excellent communicative skills. Problem-solving skills were essential for this position.

Brendan McGee Construction, Dublin/Kildare— Construction Operative

2017-2018

Short-term role in a very fast pace building site environment. The role involved work-flow management and working as part of big teams.

Junction 14 Service Station, Co.Kildare — Deli Assistant

2015-2017

Key roles and repositories involved serving customers in a very fast pace and busy environment. Great communication and interpersonal skills were a necessity. Excellent teamwork and time management skills were developed in this role.

Oxigen Environmental, Naas — Environmental Refuse Collector

2014-2015

Part of a team of environmental refuse collectors providing a refuse collection service to customers throughout county Kildare.

INTERESTS AND HOBBIES

Continued...

Motorbikes -I own a Honda CB600F/S Hornet.Would not trade it for the world.

Reading - Books are a gateway to knowledge.I mostly read educational literature, but also enjoy a bit of fiction.

REFERENCES

References are available upon request.